IDEAS OF HUMAN NATURE
RESUME
HEAR ME: OUR SUMMER
Do it.
No, I don't want to.
Just do it.
I'll just get a job, mom
With this resume?
RESUME
Yeah.
Where?
Somewhere else.
For now... I want...
You just want to do nothing, right?
Maybe?
You don't know what
you want to do yet.
For now, just do it.
But not here, mom.
Can't you go with your major?
Who wants a philosophy major?
Philosophy major?
How about a public servant?
It's a stable job
It doesn't suit me.
What suits you then?
That's what I need to figure out..
From now on... eagerly...
Eagerly my foot!.
You work here from today!
Mom...
Just for three months.
Eagerly find your job
while working here.
I will raise your allowance.
Hurry up, deliveries piled up!
Just go.
Mom, What's that?
Who put that hideous
thing on my scooter?
I did.
My scooter's not for delivery.
It is now. Go deliver now!
MI-JEONG'S LUNCHBOX
What do you think?
RICE LUNCH BOX
Good.
Good? Really?
Did I do good?
Good job, my boy!
Should've asked me before...
Do you know where the pool is?
I can't hear.
I didn't expect this
skill to come in handy.
Swimming pool.
Where is it?
The entrance.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Ga-eul, finally under 30 seconds.
- Really?
- You made it.
You broke your record.
I'm the best.
Such a show off.
I need to go! I'm late for work.
Let me know if any
orders are missing.
Let me check.
It's all good, Have a nice day.
Hi.
I was
over there
delivering.
I saw you.
That person.
Is she a swimmer, too?
Who?
She was walking with a stopwatch.
She was with you.
No, she is not a swimmer.
Is she your friend?
No, she is my older sister.
And... name?
Are you trying to pick her up?
No, no.
Well...
Kind of.
My name? Or my sister's?
Your sister.
No, I mean both.
Both...
Are you flirting with both of us?
No, no, no.
My name is Seo Ga-eul.
This is my sign name.
My sister name is Seo Yeo-reum.
And her sign name.
Phone number...
Your sister's?
Ask her yourself.
I'm back.
- Welcome back.
- Good work.
Wait a minute.
- Mom.
- Yeah?
- Is that for delivery?
-Yes.
I'll go.
- Delivery.
- Thank you so much.
Hi.
Swimming pool...
Delivery.
Hi.
Can I take a look?
I'm a master of none,
but jack of all trades.
Yes, if it doesn't bother you.
This is carburetor engine
Old oil makes dirt pile up inside.
After cleaning, it should be okay
Thank you.
Does it take long?
About an hour?
We can't do it here.
Are you in a hurry?
Then take mine.
I will fix this up.
You don't need to!
You must be busy...
No!
Use mine. Let's meet
and exchange later.
Thank you.
No...
We need to change scooters.
Give me your phone,
I will give you my number.
My bad.
Don't forget to text me.
Okay.
Fix this up.
What's this Vespa knock off?
Engine is dirty and
coil doesn't look good either
Yeah.
Pad needs replacement, too.
- You can fix it up, right?
- Of course, I can.
Tomorrow?
Tomorrow.
Early morning.
- You need it fast?
- Yeah very.
And, make it like brand new.
Bye.
- Hey.
- Yeah?
What's up?
Something's up.
- What?
- What is it?
Nothing.
There's something.
Yes but no.
There is something for sure.
SCOOTER WILL BE FIXED
BY TOMORROW MORNING
WHERE AND WHEN SHOULD WE MEET?
Hey!
- Goofing around again!
- You surprised me!
Go deliver.
Why me?
Mom told me to, and I tell you to.
Your scooter color changed?
Where do you want to go by plane?
To Olympics.
I want to go to the
Olympics with my sister.
That's great.
Thank you.
SCOOTER WILL BE FIXED
BY TOMORROW MORNING
ARE YOU BUSY?
PLEASE TEXT ME BACK.
YEO-REUM?!
Hey, this isn't
your house, you know.
Home became work now
and I need some rest.
You are going to
keep doing delivery?
For now, yeah.
I should help them out,
while I think things through.
Yeah,
Save up now and you'll be off the hook.
Did you fix the scooter?
All fixed up.
Take it when you leave.
Who has your scooter then?
Who is it?
I don't really want to know.
For real.
You look like a fool.
What's that?
You do delivery, too?
My scooter broke so I borrowed it.
Mine is shabby.
Aren't you tired?
You broke a record today.
Not tired at all.
How's international sign language lesson?
It's so hard for me.
It's confusing.
But I can learn it quickly,
to go to Olympics with you.
The Olympics is just a dream.
Getting into the qualifiers
is already a win.
You can make it to the Olympics.
Okay.
I'm serious,
Fine. Let's go. I'm hungry.
You are not listening to me?
I'm half listening.
You little...
PLEASE TEXT ME BACK
YEO-REUM?! HELLO??
SCOOTER IS ALL FIXED?! HEY!!
ARE YOU A THIEF?!!
SORRY, I WAS BUSY YESTERDAY...
THAT'S FINE.
SCOOTER IS ALL FIXED!
REALLY? THANK YOU SO MUCH
Scooter owner?
A girl?
WHEN SHOULD WE MEET?
Wow, a girl.
Is she pretty?
Hold on.
- Is she pretty?
- Hold on.
HOW ABOUT AT 10?
LET'S MEET AT THAT ALLEY
What's so funny?
It's nothing, let's eat.
Done. It's perfect.
"Lee-Yong-Jun"
It's so clean like brand new.
I washed it this morning.
Thank you.
How much for the repair?
No need. It was a simple fix.
But...
It's really okay.
I am
26 years old.
You?
I'm also 26 years old.
Great.
Instead of the repair fee
how about we just be friends?
Why?
Sign language doesn't have
honorific tense anyways.
We spoke like friends already.
Is that okay?
Your sign name matches you.
I'm not a strange person.
Yesterday,
I asked your sister about you.
I wanted to be friends with you.
I'm sorry.
That's okay.
That's why your
sign name is 'smile'.
I don't even know your name.
My name is Yong-jun.
My sign name is...
This.
Because you like to take pictures?
Take a picture of
my face and save it?
Now that we are friends..
- Shall-we grab a bite?
-  A bite?
Or rather...
ice coffee?
You fixed my scooter. My treat
Thank you.
Sorry. I have to run.
Give me. Let me throw it out.
Is it okay?
It's okay.
Thanks.
Busy all the time?
A little? Studying
and part-time job.
Studying... and part-time job.
See you later.
Is he seeing someone?
Oh. Who?
How would I know?
It better not be Jae-jin
What-the...
DID YOU EAT LUNCH?
HAVING A SANDWICH AT A CONVENIENCE STORE
YOU SHOULD HAVE A PROPER MEAL
Beer time, dude
Hello! I'm here.
What's he doing?
Look at him.
He is making all this fuss.
Why?
It's surprisingly good.
- Really?
-Yes.
It's good.
He should really work
here than getting a job.
Right?
Honey, let's employ him full-time.
Shush.
This is so much.
I didn't know what you like.
So, I put a little bit of everything.
I like all these.
Really?
I'm so relieved.
Go on and eat.
How is it?
Really?
Let's eat together.
I can eat at the store.
Thank you for the meal.
Enjoy your food.
Take your time.
How much is it?
You don't have to pay.
I can't do that.
You sell these lunchboxes.
Is this enough?
Thank you. It was delicious.
I ate it. I should
take care of it.
Bye.
Not here to sell.
I'm back.
Sold a lot today.
- You.
- What?
Why did you cook all of a sudden?
No reason.
You are really going to
work here for ever?
No.
But that's not a bad idea.
No. You'll work here only for
3 months and then find a job.
That was the plan,
but I can help out more.
We don't need help.
So, stay out of kitchen.
You were the one
forcing me to work here.
Who is it?
Ah, it's a friend.
I'm heading out.
Definitely a girl.
Girl?
Girl.
Who?
Yong-jun.
Yong-jun is pretty for
a boy, but not a girl.
I mean he is seeing a 'girl'.
He is in love.
GA-EUL'S TRAINING FEE
500,000 WON BY JULY 25
25TH SEOUL CITY HALL SWIMMING COMPETITION
LET'S GO, GA-EUL
- Get out of the pool.
- You! Get out of the pool.
How can our kids use
the same pool with them?
It's ridiculous.
- Can't you speak?
- You either?
- Bring your coach here now.
- Are you swearing at me right now?
You all get out!
What's going on here?
Are you the coach?
Any problem?
Empty the pool. Our
kids need to practice.
This is our scheduled time.
Our kids are scheduled, too.
You are supposed to
use the outside lanes.
How can our kids
swim with disabled kids?
Are you alright? Let's get out.
I'm fine.
- What if our kids get sick?
- Why would they get sick?!
No one has skin disease.
Non-sense.
We will come back later.
Clean up and bleach all.
What did you say?
Clean up everything with bleach.
Disinfect it all
You don't have manners.
Ji-Kyung, get changed.
Hey, let's go.
Take care.
See you later.
- Hey.
- What is it?
Deaf can read faces and lips.
So what?
We can hear. Deaf can see.
They can't hear, but
can see much better.
So what?
They saw everything you said.
So, what are you going to do?
Did I say something wrong?
Who are you?
What are you doing?
Are you taking pictures?
Let me see your face.
What are you doing?
Are you crazy?
Illegal parking in a disabled
zone will be fined 100,000 won.
Don't you dare report this!
REPORT FOR ILLEGAL PARKING
Is your sister okay?
You saw?
She's okay.
How about you?
Me? I'm okay.
It happens from time to time...
but...
I can't get used to it.
Enjoy your meal.
The world is so stubborn.
We are just missing sounds.
It's a whole different world.
Can't get in, Can't get out.
It will probably never change.
Why are you here?
Let's go have fun!
It's ok. I will stand.
Can you ask
Ga-eul if she is tired?
Aren't you tired?
I'm excited! Fun is never tiring.
She says fun is never tiring.
Thanks.
Can she miss work, you ask?
Don't you have to go to work?
It's okay. I got a day off.
She's got a day off.
Amazing!
Why here?
Night air feels cool.
I was feeling down today.
Thanks for such a fun time.
Let me head home.
You take your time.
What?
Shall we walk?
HOW MUCH MONEY DID YOU SPEND
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT. IT'S ON ME
WE HAD FUN TOGETHER.
WE SHOULD ALL PAY
IT'S REALLY OKAY
DON'T SAY THAT. TELL ME HOW MUCH
SORRY. THEN 30,000 WON
GA-EUL TOLD ME TO
SEND YOU 50,000 WON
THANKS. LET'S DO IT AGAIN
SURE, AGAIN!
When did I say that?
You know...
Why do you split money every time?
You can treat him next time.
I don't feel comfortable.
What?
Beer?
Are you dating him?
No. We are just friends.
- I don't think he sees that way.
- We are just friends.
What?
To sleep. So sleepy.
WHAT SOUND DO YOU
WANT TO HEAR THE MOST?
YOUR VOICE...
I DON'T KNOW. I WILL LET YOU KNOW LATER.
YOU MUST BE TIRED. HEAD TO BED.
OKAY. IT WAS SO
MUCH FUN TODAY, NIGHT!
You are going late than usual?
We moved to a
different swimming pool.
Because of that lady?
Yeah. Too many complaints.
That crazy people.
Yeah.
We're not afraid of
poop, we just avoid it.
What are you eating?
Bread!
Where's the new pool?
Old City Swimming Pool.
That's a little far.
I know!
Have a nice day!
You too.
SEOUL SPORT CENTER
- It's so lousy.
- It's lousy.
Of course, I can help.
She's the one I was
telling you about.
- What's her record?
- 28 seconds.
28 seconds?
Will she be competing
in general division?
The upcoming Seoul
City Hall competition?
She will make it to the
qualifiers for National Team
Wow.
Well, let her
practice here freely
Thanks, Right
until the qualifiers.
Let's learn about
international sign language.
I'm hungry. Let's
go home and eat.
25TH SEOUL CITY HALL
SWIMMING COMPETITION
I'll do it.
Lane 2 Kim Su-min,
Gangwon Sports Council.
Lane 3 Woo Hee-yeon,
Halla Athletic.
Lane 4 Joo Hye-reon,
Incheon City Hall.
Lane 5 Jeong Woo-sun,
Stroke Seoul.
Lane 6 Sunwoo Ye-ji,
Gyeongbuk Provincial Office.
Lane 7 Seo Ga-eul,
Hope Swimming Federation.
Lane 8 Ahn Da-hee,
Jeju City Hall.
Take your mark.
She did it!
SEO GA-EUL 27.87 SECONDS
1ST PLACE - SEO GA-EUL/HOPE
SWIMMING FEDERATION - 27.87 SECONDS
Just one more second to go.
What's that?
Gold medal.
Ga-eul beat her personal
best in a general division.
Congratulations!
Wait. Sorry.
Sorry.
If she can reduce
one more second,
she can go to the qualifiers
If she ranks in the qualifiers,
she can be in the national team
Then she can really
go to the Olympics?
Yes. Isn't she amazing?
Yes. You and Ga-eul both!
Shall we celebrate?
Oh... She needs to rest..
And I need to prepare dinner, too.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
You go have fun.
I can see him next time.
Sorry.
Just wait for 30 minutes!
- What took you so long?
- What is it? I'm super busy.
Deliver this, quick.
- No way I'm busy.
- Just this once. Please..
- I'm really busy. I can't
- Just once!
I'm really busy.
I'm sorry, I can't.
- A blind date?
- This is the address?
- Be careful.
- Got it.
This person is really freaky,
so just leave it at the door.
I usually do that anyway.
How freaky?
Worst of the worst.
Just don't encounter.
- Blind date on next Tuesday?
- Just go quick!
I'm going.
Looks good on you.
- Feels strange.
- So pretty.
I like this better.
- It's boring.
- No, it's cool.
- Nah.
- Why?!
Is this ok?
Oh la la.
Why? Something on my face?
No, no.
What should we do?
Are you hungry? Shall we go eat?
Do I...
Look like a hungry monster?
No, no. Why?
You always ask me if I ate.
"Eat something," "Let's eat"
Sorry.
Maybe because I'm
son of the lunchbox shop.
Then, what should we do?
Let's go hang out.
- Isn't here great, right?
- Yes, love it.
Ga-eul and I used to hang
out here when we were kids
Did you live here?
My parents still live here.
I sometimes come
and help my parents.
And I come here
when I feel puzzled.
Gazing at the river helps me clear my mind.
HOW'S YOUR DATE GOING?
NO NEED TO REPLY!
So, what do you desire to do?
- Desire to do?
- Yeah.
My sister going to
the Olympics one day?
Not your sister.
What you really want
Hmm.
Seeing my sister
going to the Olympics?
After that? What do you want to try?
After that?
Me?
Well, I have no idea.
Actually, I've never
thought about what I want.
You really haven't?
Yeah.
How about you?
Me?
I have no idea either, honestly.
As a teenager, I just enjoyed
hanging out with friends
I barely graduated university.
When time came to get a job,
I wasn't sure what I wanted
Still, I submitted some resumes.
Obviously, not a chance!
I have no specialty nor a dream job.
Exactly like me.
Yeah.
Then, how about...
We find something together?
What?
You know...
Neither of us has found our dream yet.
If we try out various
things together.
Maybe we will reach somewhere.
Let's do it!
Yong-jun.
Thanks for being a friend.
Hello! Anyone there?
Hey...
You thanked me for being a friend.
But I...
You...
At first sight.
Sorry. Hold on.
HOSPITAL ER NOTIFICATION -
SEO GA-EUL IS TRANSFERRED
TO THE EMERGENCY ROOM
FOR SUFFOCATION FROM A FIRE
I'm sorry.
I inhaled only a bit of smoke.
Mom and dad will worry.
So don't tell them..
I am really okay.
You are not okay!
It is okay to say not okay.
You have an important
competition coming up..
I'm sorry.
No, I'm the one who's sorry.
I should have been there for you.
I'm really okay.
I shall be discharged soon.
What if you can't
make it to qualifiers?
You trained so hard for
10 years in the cold water...
No,
I feel warmer and
relaxed in the water now.
So, don't worry.
I set a personal best today.
I can rest a bit.
YONG-JUN :
YEO-REUM, IS EVERYTHING OKAY?
We will head home now.
Okay. See you later.
I CAN GET DISCHARGED
ALREADY? I'M ON MY WAY
YOU DON'T NEED TO COME.
COACH IS PICKING ME UP
I'LL GO STRAIGHT TO PRACTICE
IF YOU PICKED UP
THIS PHONE,
PLEASE BRING IT TO
MI-JEONG'S LUNCHBOXES
Are you okay?
Should we get something
yummy before going home?
Go ahead. I have plans.
Can't I come along, too?
Why?
I need to talk with my friends.
I'M GOING TO PRACTICE, YOU
DON'T HAVE TO COME ANYMORE
Are you okay?
What happened?
Why can't I reach you?
Didn't you see my texts?
I didn't.
I'm sorry, but don't come here anymore.
Stop texting me too.
Why are you acting like this?
Did something happen?
Nothing happened
Then, did I do something wrong?
No.
Then, why?
Tell me. I need to know..
You don't have to know!
Do you know how worried I was?
If you do this again to
me, what should I do?
How can you not think
about my feelings?
Do I have to care
about your feelings too?
I barely can take care
of those around me.
Please, just go.
Do I...
Am I
a burden to you?
Hope he will do deliveries.
- You do it.
- Me?
Go quick.
Is that for delivery?
- I will go.
- Sure.
He's alright.
It's over.
I can't make it to qualifiers.
I'm sorry.
Ga-eul, I'm sorry.
It's my fault.
Because of me, your dream...
What about your dream?
What is your dream?
Do you only care about my dream?
Your dream is my dream.
Why is my dream your dream?
My life is mine to live.
Why do you stake
your life for my dream?
What do you mean?
Why do you say that?
Don't you understand?
You take me here
back and forth every day.
You do jobs to pay
for my training fees.
You spend all your
hours at the pool.
Is your life here?
You are here solely because of me.
Do you know how
that makes me feel?
I'm drifting away...
Me...
My life... My dream!
I can't rest when I want to
I can't quit even if I want to.
Rather than not
reaching to the qualifiers.
It hurts more to disappoint you.
It's too hard feeling
sorry all the time.
Hey yo!
What's wrong?
Something happened?
That delivery you asked me to do?
Wasn't it your girlfriend's house?
Who's the freaky person?
Did you see him?
Nah, I just left the food
at the door and left.
Who is it?
Her younger brother.
Younger brother?
Oh, that freaky person was
her younger brother.
That must have been tough for you.
Whatever.
It's all over now.
What are you saying?
I got dumped.
No, that can't be.
It's over.
It's not over until it's over.
What? It's over, so it's over.
Call her and say you are sorry.
Say everything in the world is your fault.
I can't do that.
Why not? Just call her.
Just do it once for me.
Come on.
She's hearing impaired.
She told me not to come nor text.
I see.
I didn't know that.
It must have been
really tough for you, man.
Hey, man. Do you know...
If the freaky younger
brother is also...
the same?
Yes.
Is something wrong?
No, nothing's wrong
Ga-eul is training
and eating well.
No, I'm asking about you.
Mom. Dad.
Why did you bring
me into this world?
Because, it's you!
Of course.
When you had me,
weren't you afraid
of the disability?
Why would we be afraid?
Because it's hard.
It's not hard.
Was it hard for you?
No way. Not at all.
My son got dumped
I thought so.
You can tell?
Very.
Which girl broke my boy's heart?
For her...
Her younger sister
is everything to her.
Does a lot of part-time jobs
diligently living person.
Even having no time to eat.
She...
She have never thought
of what she desires to do.
Why?
She's too kind.
Always take care of others but herself.
I think that's why she dumped me.
Not to hurt me.
Why should it hurt?
She can't hear.
Huh?
Hearing impaired.
Can't speak either.
Mom.
I feel like you don't.
want me here to help you.
Right.
Why?
It's nice to have help.
It is, but.
It's a burden seeing
you only care for others.
But still, I'm useful
around here, right?
Do you know what
you are really doing?
Being a good daughter?
No.
What is it, then?
S-Y-M-P-A-T-H-I-Z-I-N-G
Why do you say that?
I'm just looking
out for my family.
I know, but.
No one can live someone
else's life for them.
Family trusts each other and wait.
I want you to help
when we ask you to.
I'm sorry.
Mom, I...
It's okay, Yeo-reum.
I want my daughter
to live her life.
Not as Ga-eul's
sister nor our daughter.
Just as you.
- I'm sorry.
Looks like summer
birds aren't back yet
I guess so
I don't see any of it.
I wanted to see them.
Why aren't you seeing that guy?
I don't want to date anyone.
Why?
Because of hearing impaired?
Because of me?
I don't want to be
a burden to you.
You are never a burden to me.
I mean it.
I want to see you
smiling like this.
Your smile makes me happy.
In the water, you smile like that.
Then, can't you just trust me?
I will start over, and
I can do it by myself.
Okay, I trust you.
Then, go date him.
You are afraid about not being by his
side since you need to take care of me
I won't give up swimming.
So don't give up on him too.
What's up with Yong-jun?
Is he dumped?
Yeah.
No way.
Should I...?
She can't hear.
You mean with her ears?
Then what?
You hear with your nose?
With nose?
She is hearing impaired.
She can't hear and speak.
That's why she dumped him.
She didn't want to drag him down.
Should I go talk to her?
Are you okay with it?
With what?
She being deaf.
What about it?
I'm okay as long as
she's a good person.
Being able to hear and speak doesn't
mean they know how to communicate
Right.
This is why I fell
in love with you.
Fell in what?
Yeah, here's an example.
What are you saying?
I'm sorry, Yeo-reum.
I'm sorry for saying sorry
I'm sorry because
because I didn't really know.
I thought I knew
but I didn't.
That's...
why I'm sorry.
And I...
Didn't know I might
be a burden to you.
That I'm sorry, too.
That's why...
We drifted apart a little bit.
In fact, I got dumped.
But...
I can not let you go.
I won't let you go.
You don't take care of yourself,
so I want to take care of you.
Also...
I like your smile,
and I want to make you
Smile.
So, what I wanted to say is...
That... I...
Do you
want to work
at my parents' store?
Why?
I think it would be
fun to work together.
I can't hear.
Would your parents
be okay with that?
They will see.
How good a person you are!
How hard you work!
Yes?
Yes.
Come in, please.
Please, have a seat.
She's so pretty.
Mom, dad, this is Yeo-reum.
And her sign name is this.
Because, she smiles a lot.
Oh I forgot. That thing?
Look here.
I'm Yong-jun's dad.
I'm Yong-jun's mom.
Nice to meet you.
Yong-jun is childish and a bit Idiotic.
Mom.
He can be dense and
clueless sometimes.
But, he is also a
very reliable person.
Yong-jun eats a lot
and poops a lot.
Stop it.
Why don't you two get back together?
Why do you ask her that?
She's here for a job interview.
You can work and
date at the same time
Or be a working honey bees.
Yes, I'd like that.
I said I'd like that.
She can speak!
- She speaks!
- Uh-uh?
I thought you can't hear?
I can. I thought you can't hear.
So you heard what
I said at the pool?
You heard it...
So, yes to getting back
with me?
Or getting the job?
I...
like you.
- What did she say?
- Be quiet.
What did she say?
Stop asking!
She made this sign.
I was fooled by my
senior in university.
Huh?
He said that sign
language is a body language
that can be used
anywhere in the world.
So, I must learn if I
plan to go backpacking.
That's it?
That's why I learned it.
Just because of that?
So...
Among your family...
Only you can hear?
Yes.
I thought everyone was like that.
But, I was wrong.
Only my family was
living in a different world.
Don't act and live as if you are
also hearing-impaired like us.
You're different from us, but
you are not in a different world.
We share the world
called 'family' together.
Hear me?
For us, meeting you girls...
Is the best thing that
happened in our lives.
For me...
being born as your daughter
is the best thing that happened in my life.
For me...
meeting you
is the best thing that
happened in my life.
DIRECTED AND ADAPTED BY JO SEON HO
HONG KYUNG
ROH YOON-SEO
KIM MIN-JU
JUNG HYE-YOUNG / HYUN BONG-SIK / JUNG YONG-JU
Are you alright?
Hold tight!
I like you.